## **TIMOTHY MUI MUTINDA**

P.O. Box 10781-00200, Nairobi. +254 722 433 736, +254 737 477 210

tmmutinda@gmail.com, tmmutinda@yahoo.com

**Date of Birth** – 1968 : **Home County** – Kitui : **Constituency** – Mwingi Central **Marital Status** – Married with 3 Children

# **Key Qualifications**

Mr. Timothy Mutinda has more than seventeen years' experience in Development Planning, Training, Research, Impact Assessments, Monitoring and Evaluation and a practitioner of participatory approaches such as Participatory Rural Appraisal (PRA), Participatory Learning and Action (PLA) Approaches, Logical Framework Approach (LFA) and Project Cycle Management (PCM). He has extensive hands on experience in working with European Union formats of project planning, proposal development, monitoring and evaluation systems used by most Funding Agencies. Over the years, Mr. Mutinda has carried out many consultancy Assignments for both Governmental and Nongovernmental Agencies in East African Region covering Kenya, Tanzania, Uganda, South Sudan and South-western Ethiopia.

Currently, Mr. Timothy Mutinda is the Administration Manager at Kenya Association of Music Producers (KAMP) a Collective Management Organisation (CMO) involved in the management of related rights to the copyright on behalf of music producers in Kenya. To enhance his skills, Mr. Mutinda attended a 3-week training course on copyright and related rights in the global economy in Stockholm, Sweden from 9<sup>th</sup> to 28<sup>th</sup> August 2009 and a one-week follow-up in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia from 22<sup>nd</sup> to 26<sup>th</sup> February 2010.

## **Core Competencies**

- Strategic Business and Development Planning
- Project Management,
   Monitoring & Evaluation
- Workshop Facilitation
- BusinessAdministration
- Human Resource
   Management
- Community Mobilisation
- Proposal Writing
- Report Writing
- Training using Participatory Approaches
- Intellectual Property / Copyright Management

# **Work Experience**

# 1. Kenya Association of Music Producers (KAMP) - 1<sup>st</sup> March 2010 to-date

## **Administration Manager**

KAMP, a Collective Management Organisation, which collects royalties and licence fees from users of sound recording musical works on behalf of record companies i.e. producers of sound recordings. Reporting to the General Manager, responsible for overall day-to-day management of the organisation's secretariat, human resource functions including recruitment of staff, development of work plans, implementation, monitoring & evaluation of the organisation's activities, developing proposals, preparing relevant reports, procurement of services from contracting third party service providers, taking minutes during Board of Directors' meetings, etc.

#### **Contributions to the Organisation**

- Established the secretariat of the organisation as a volunteer consultant from June 2008
- Establishment of operational systems of the organisation through development of a draft operational manual, which includes aspects of HR, procurement, financial management, etc.

# 2. Participatory Training Promotions Institute Ltd. (PARTPRO) – 2011 & 2012 Workshop Facilitator

Facilitated in three regional workshops in Mombasa, Nakuru and Kisumu on dissemination and review of three manuals on financial operations for CDF projects, Guidelines on Project Management and a community based Monitoring and Evaluation manual from 12<sup>th</sup> to 28<sup>th</sup> June 2012. The workshops were organised by the Ministry of State for Planning, National Development and Vision 2030.

Participated in beneficiary views and data collection in 3 districts of Busia County i.e. Busia, Butula and Teso North using Participatory data collection tools. Mr. Mutinda was the leader of the team that worked in Butula and Teso North Districts from 15<sup>th</sup> September to 1<sup>st</sup> October 2011. The exercise was organised by the Ministry of State for Planning, National Development and Vision 2030 under PALWECO Programme in Busia County.

# 3. Guiding Systems Consult Ltd - 1<sup>st</sup> April 1996 to 2009

## **Associate Consultant**

My duties and responsibilities were preparation of consultancy bidding proposals, facilitation of Participatory Planning, Evaluation and Training Workshops and Preparation of training materials, data processing, analysis and preparation of reports.

# 4. Guiding Systems Consult Ltd – 1<sup>st</sup> April 1994 to 31<sup>st</sup> March 1996

Was in permanent employment with GS Consult Ltd as a moderator/trainer & documentation. **Contributions to the Organisation's Clients (Examples)** 

- Facilitated in the development and implementation of District Strategy Development
   Programmes under the ASAL Programmes in Laikipia, Keiyo & Marakwet in collaboration
   with relevant Government Ministries (1994 to 1995) funded by the Netherlands and
   Kenyan Government.
- Facilitated in the development and implementation of District Development Strategy Programmes in Kasulu District in Western Tanzania (1997 to 1998) funded by the Austrian and Tanzanian Government.
- Facilitated in Development and implementation of District Strategy in Ngorongoro District in Northern Tanzania (2001 to 2004) funded by the Austrian and Tanzanian Government under the Decentralization Programme.
- Was the socio-economic expert during the implementation of water harvesting pilot project in the Karamoja Cluster Region in NW Kenya, NE Uganda, Southern Sudan and SW Ethiopia. (March 2005 – August 2006) funded by the African Development Bank (AfDB) and implemented by IGAD.
- In a team of three Consultants from Guiding Systems Consult, based in Nairobi, participated in the Planning and Budgeting Workshops on Water for Eastern Equitoria held in Torit, South Sudan from 18<sup>th</sup> to 29<sup>th</sup> May 2015.

#### **Additional Skills**

Computer literate – Proficient in MS Office packages - MS Word, MS Excel and Power Point Presentations

## **Education**

- Master of Business Administration (HR): University of Nairobi (continuing): May 2012 to date (currently working on his Research Project)
- Bachelor of Arts (Sociology and Econ): Egerton University: September 1989 October 1992
- K.A.C.E: Shimo-la-Tewa School, Mombasa: March 1987 December 1988
- K.C.E: Technical High School, Mombasa: January 1983 November 1986
- C.P.E Magarini Primary School, Malindi : January 1976 December 1982

## **Other Training**

- Participated in a 3-week training on copyright and related rights in the global economy in Stockholm, Sweden (August 2009) and one-week follow-up on the same in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia in February 2010.
- Participated in a two-day Advocacy Competence training course from 23<sup>rd</sup> to 24<sup>th</sup> September 2008, conducted by the Business Advocacy Fund (BAF) in Nairobi.
- Participated in an Institutional Competence Course from 2<sup>nd</sup> to 3<sup>rd</sup> December 2008, conducted by the Business Advocacy Fund (BAF) in Nairobi.
- Participated in a one week Participatory Planning Training by Community Organisation Consultants (COC) Ltd. From January 30<sup>th</sup> to February 3<sup>rd</sup> 1995, Nairobi.
- Participated in a one week 'Sharing Forum on how to Bridge the Gap Between Community Participation and Policy Making', organised by Participatory Methodologies Forum of Kenya (PAMFORK) and the British Council from 4<sup>th</sup> – 8<sup>th</sup> August 1997.
- Participated in a three-week Training of Trainers (TOT) course on Community Participation in Policy Development (March 1998).

# Languages

English : Very good (both spoken and written)
Swahili : Excellent (both spoken and written)
Kamba : Excellent (both spoken and written)

#### **Hobbies**

Travelling and scenery viewing, drama, listening and playing music, photography, making friends

## Referees

# 1. Mr. Stanley Mbagathi

Director, Guiding Systems Consult, P O Box 72387-00200, Nairobi-Kenya. Cell: +254 722 808023 (Nairobi, Kenya) Email: smbagathi@gmail.com

# 2. Mr. Gathii Muraguri

Management & Development Consultant, P.O. Box 61010, Nairobi-Kenya. Cell: +254 722 618956

Email: gathiimuraguri@yahoo.co.uk

#### 3. Mr. Clifford M. Wefwafwa

Chief Executive Officer Kenya Association of Music Producers P O Box 51149 - 00200, Nairobi-Kenya.

Cell: + Cell: +254 725 549393 Email: clifford@kamp.or.ke

#### **Declaration**

I declare that the information given in this document is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

T.M. Mutinda